fespa.com 2016-03-13

# Privacy policy - FESPA

This privacy notice tells you what to expect when FESPA collects personal information.

## Visitors to our websites

When someone visits [www.fespa.com](http://www.fespa.com/) we collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behaviour patterns. We do this to find out things such as the number of visitors to the various parts of the site. We collect this information in a way which does not identify anyone.

We do not make any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting either of our websites. We will not associate any data gathered from this site with any personally identifying information from any source. If we do want to collect personally identifiable information through our website, we will be up front about this. We will make it clear when we collect personal information and will explain what we intend to do with it.

## E-newsletter

We use a third party provider to deliver our monthly e-newsletter. We gather statistics around email opening and clicks using industry standard technologies including gifs to help us monitor and improve our e-newsletter.

All contacts on our marketing database may change their email preferences using the links at the bottom of every email we send, we also include a single-click unsubscribe link which will permanently block all further marketing emails from being sent.

## Security and performance

FESPA uses a third party service to help maintain the security and performance of FESPA website. To deliver this service it processes the IP addresses of visitors to FESPA website.

## Third party services

We use third party services and systems to provide some websites, as well as some functions on our own websites, and marketing functions.  These include social media platforms such as Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, Xing, LinkedIn and Google +, event registration services such as RegOnline, InfoExpo and others.  When using those systems, their standard privacy terms apply.

## People who email us

Any email sent to us, including any attachments, may be monitored and used by us for reasons of security and for monitoring compliance with office policy.  Email monitoring or blocking software may also be used. Please be aware that you have a responsibility to ensure that any email you send to us is within the bounds of the law.

## People who use FESPA services

We have to hold the details of the people who have requested services in order to provide it. However, we only use these details to provide the service the person has requested and for other closely related purposes. For example, we might use information about people who have requested a publication to carry out a survey to find out if they are happy with the level of service they received. When people do subscribe to our services, they can cancel their subscription at any time and are given an easy way of doing this.

## Job applicants, current and former FESPA employees

When individuals apply to work at FESPA, we will only use the information they supply to us to process their application and to monitor recruitment statistics. Where we want to disclose information to a third party, for example where we want to take up a reference or obtain a ‘disclosure’ from the Criminal Records Bureau we will not do so without informing them beforehand unless the disclosure is required by law.

Personal information about unsuccessful candidates will be held for 12 months after the recruitment exercise has been completed, it will then be destroyed or deleted. We retain de-personalised statistical information about applicants to help inform our recruitment activities, but no individuals are identifiable from that data.

Once a person has taken up employment with FESPA, we will compile a file relating to their employment. The information contained in this will be kept secure and will only be used for purposes directly relevant to that person’s employment. Once their employment with FESPA has ended, we will retain the file in accordance with the requirements of our retention schedule and then delete it.

## Complaints or queries

FESPA tries to meet the highest standards when collecting and using personal and business information. For this reason, we take any complaints we receive about this very seriously. We encourage people to bring it to our attention if they think that our collection or use of information is unfair, misleading or inappropriate. We would also welcome any suggestions for improving our procedures.

This privacy notice was drafted with brevity and clarity in mind. It does not provide exhaustive detail of all aspects of FESPA’s collection and use of personal information. However, we are happy to provide any additional information or explanation needed. Any requests for this should be sent to the postal address below.

## Links to other websites

This privacy notice does not cover the links within this site linking to other websites. 

## Changes to this privacy notice

We keep our privacy notice under regular review. This privacy notice was last updated on 9 December 2014.

## Contact us by post:

FESPA Ltd

Bancroft Place

10 Bancroft Road

Reigate

Surrey

United Kingdom

RH1 3AU
